usconcealedcarry.com 2019-09-03

# Privacy Policy | USCCA

Effective date: April 05, 2019

Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the http://www.usconcealedcarry.com website and the mobile application (hereinafter referred to as the “Service”).

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, the terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions.

We are strongly committed to safeguarding consumer privacy on our website. We operate under the following set of strict privacy principles:

The only information our website will obtain from you is information we need to process credit card charges of membership fees or for other purchases. That information is never revealed, resold, or made public for any reason.

Our Online Community collects information from you when you register on our site and gathers data when you participate in the forum by interacting with content there.

When registering on our community, you may be asked to enter your name and e-mail address. You may, however, visit our community without registering. Your e-mail address will be verified by an email containing a unique link. If that link is visited, we know that you control the e-mail address.

When registered and posting in the community, we record the IP address that the post originated from. We also may retain server logs which include the IP address of every request to our server.

To protect your privacy when posting or replying to messages in the community message board, your personal information and email are not revealed.

However, remember that any information that you disclose in the message board areas can be read by all other members, so exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

Personally identifiable information that you provide to us (name, e-mail or home address, etc.) is never disclosed to anyone.

## Cookies

Each time you log into our site, we store a temporary “cookie” in the browser files of your computer. This cookie is used during your online session to allow you free access to the member’s area, without repeatedly requiring you to re-enter your username and password.

Whenever you log off or leave the site, the cookies file is automatically removed.

 **Please also note:**  Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to this website. You have the option to opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). Alternatively you can opt-out of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative op out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

## External Links

In order to provide visitors with greater value, some of our pages may provide links to various third party websites.

In no case is member information or ‘cookies’ provided to the third party sites. However, keep in mind that many sites do attempt to capture visitor information when you browse those sites.

Once you leave our site, we are not able to alert you should another site attempt to gather information from your browser.

## Public Forums

Our members and non-members are able to participate on 3rd party platform forums associated with the USCCA (such as the USCCA Facebook page or the USCCA Google My Business page).

The 3rd party platforms are responsible for protecting your privacy on their platforms. For more information about these platforms, see their Privacy Policies and Terms of Use. These platforms are considered to be “public forums” so the information you post is “public information”. Public information is information that is public and can be seen by anyone, at anytime, and can be shared on any platform or website.

Remember that any information that you disclose on a 3rd party public forum is public information so exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information such as your name or pictures of yourself.

The USCCA reserves the right to utilize any posts, comments, or reviews made by any person on any USCCA webpage, the USCCA community pages, and on any 3rd party platform forum associated with the USCCA for marketing purposes.

## Security

Our website and community have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We employ strict security measures to safeguard online transactions; personal information is stored in a secured database and is always sent via an encrypted Internet channel.

## Choice/Opt-In

Our site gives users the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from us. You can be assured that we never reveal, sell, or make available your email address to anyone for any purpose.

This site also gives users the option to remove their information from our database in order to stop receiving communications or our service.

## Other

If you have questions regarding our privacy policy, feel free to let us know, using our [Customer Service](https://organic.usccadev.com/about/contact/) page.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our site and not to information collected offline.

## Definitions

  *  **Service**  
Service means the http://www.usconcealedcarry.com website and the mobile application operated by Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc
  *  **Personal Data**  
Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).
  *  **Usage Data**  
Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).
  *  **Cookies**  
Cookies are small files stored on your device (computer or mobile device).
  *  **Data Controller**  
Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.

  *  **Data Processors (or Service Providers)**  
Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

  *  **Data Subject (or User)**  
Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

## Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

 **Personal Data**

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Phone number
  * Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
  * Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or the instructions provided in any email we send.

 **Usage Data**

We may also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service or when you access the Service by or through a mobile device (“Usage Data”).

This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

When you access the Service with a mobile device, this Usage Data may include information such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device unique ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browser you use, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

 **Location Data**

We may use and store information about your location if you give us permission to do so (“Location Data”). We use this data to provide features of our Service, to improve and customize our Service.

You can enable or disable location services when you use our Service at any time by way of your device settings.

 **Tracking & Cookies Data**

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and we hold certain information.

Cookies are files with a small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Other tracking technologies are also used such as beacons, tags and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  *  **Session Cookies.**  We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  *  **Preference Cookies.**  We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  *  **Security Cookies.**  We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
  *  **Advertising Cookies.**  Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

## Use of Data

Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

## Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), Delta Defense, LLC and United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc.’s legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

Delta Defense, LLC or United States concealed Carry Association, Inc. may process your Personal Data because:

  * We need to perform a contract with you
  * You have given us permission to do so
  * The processing is in our legitimate interests and it is not overridden by your rights
  * For payment processing purposes
  * To comply with the law

## Retention of Data

Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer periods.

## Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ from those of your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Delta Defense, LLC and United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. will take all the steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Disclosure of Data

### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Delta Defense, LLC or United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### Legal Requirements

Delta Defense, LLC or United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Delta Defense, LLC or United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc.
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

## Security of Data

The security of your data is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Our Policy on “Do Not Track” Signals under the California Online Protection Act (CalOPPA)

We do not support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

## Your Data Protection Rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Delta Defense, LLC and United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. aim to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed about what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

  *  **The right to access, update or delete the information we have on you.**  Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.
  *  **The right of rectification.**  You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
  *  **The right to object.**  You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.
  *  **The right of restriction.**  You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.
  *  **The right to data portability.**  You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.
  *  **The right to withdraw consent.**  You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Delta Defense, LLC or United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

## Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), provide the Service on our behalf, perform Service-related services or assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

 **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

 **Firebase**

Firebase is analytics service provided by Google Inc.

You may opt-out of certain Firebase features through your mobile device settings, such as your device advertising settings or by following the instructions provided by Google in their Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

We also encourage you to review the Google’s policy for safeguarding your data: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>.

For more information on what type of information Firebase collects, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

### Advertising

We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.

 **Google AdSense & DoubleClick Cookie**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet.

You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/>

### Behavioral Remarketing

Delta Defense, LLC on behalf of the United States Concealed Carry Association, Inc. may use remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

 **Google Ads (AdWords)**

Google Ads (AdWords) remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>

Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on – <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> – for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

 **Bing Ads Remarketing**

Bing Ads remarketing service is provided by Microsoft Inc.

You can opt-out of Bing Ads interest-based ads by following their instructions: <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads>

You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Microsoft by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/PrivacyStatement>

 **Twitter**

Twitter remarketing service is provided by Twitter Inc.

You can opt-out from Twitter’s interest-based ads by following their instructions: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405>

You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Twitter by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://twitter.com/privacy>

 **Facebook**

Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc.

You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: <https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950>

To opt-out from Facebook’s interest-based ads, follow these instructions from Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>

Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada <http://youradchoices.ca/> or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>, or opt-out using your mobile device settings.

For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

 **Pinterest**

Pinterest remarketing service is provided by Pinterest Inc.

You can opt-out from Pinterest’s interest-based ads by enabling the “Do Not Track” functionality of your web browser or by following Pinterest instructions: <http://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalization-and-data>

You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Pinterest by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>

### Payments

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

The payment processors we work with are:

 **Stripe**  
Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>

 **CyberSource**  
Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://www.cybersource.com/privacy/>

## Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

## Children’s Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).  If you are under the age of 18mplease do not use our Service or access our website or send any user information to us

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

  * By email: info@uscca.com
  * By phone number: 800-674-9779
  * By mail: 1000 Freedom Way, West Bend, WI 53095
